Every night has a soundtrack.
Nick and Norah's Infinite Playlist is a romance, comedy,
music film directed by Peter Sollett.
Nick cannot stop obsessing over his ex-girlfriend, Tris, until Tris'
friend Norah suddenly shows interest in him at a club.
Thus begins an odd night filled with ups and downs as the two keep running into Tris and her new boyfriend
while searching for Norah's drunken friend, Caroline, with help from Nick's band mates.
As the night winds down, the two have to figure
out what they want from each other.
Nick, played by Michael Cera.
Norah, played by Kat Dennings.
Thom, played by Aaron Yoo.
Dev, played by Rafi Gavron.
Caroline, played by Ari Graynor.
Tris, played by Alexis Dziena.
Nick & Norah's Infinite Playlist is a 2008 American romantic comedy-drama film directed by Peter Sollett and
starring Michael Cera, Kat Dennings, Alexis Dziena, Ari Graynor, Aaron Yoo and Jay Baruchel.
Written by Lorene Scafaria and based on the novel of the same name by Rachel Cohn and David Levithan, the story tells of teenagers
Nick (Cera) and Norah (Dennings), who meet when Norah asks Nick to pretend to be her boyfriend for five minutes.
Over the course of the night, they try to find their favorite band's
secret show and search for Norah's drunken best friend.
The film came into development in 2003 when producer Kerry Kohansky Roberts
found Cohn and Levithan's novel and decided to adapt it for film.
Scafaria was hired to write the script in 2005, and
Sollett signed on to direct the film in 2006.
Principal photography took place over 29 days from October to December
2007, primarily in Manhattan and Brooklyn, New York City.
The film premiered on September 6, 2008, at the 2008 Toronto International
Film Festival and was released theatrically on October 3, 2008.
It tripled its US$10 million budget with a total gross of US$33.5 million.
An accompanying soundtrack was released on September 23, 2008, and the
film was released on DVD and Blu-ray on February 3, 2009.
It attracted generally positive reviews from critics and received nominations for three
Satellite Awards, one GLAAD Media Award, one MTV Movie Award and one Golden Reel Award.
The film explores themes of concert, new jersey, based on
novel or book, one night, secret location.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.